{"name": "71H  2014-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Danica is trying to encourage her classmates to donate books for the fund-raiser and book-drive for the local library. Danica will donate $35.00, plus $0.07 for each book donated by her classmates. Which of the following equations gives Danica's donation, d dollars, if b books are donated by her classmates?", "choices": {"A": "d = 35 + 0.07b", "B": "d = 35 + 0.7b", "C": "d = 35 + 7b", "D": "d = 35.07b", "E": "d = 42b"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. If , then z = ?", "choices": {"A": "-64", "B": "-12", "C": "-4", "D": "4", "E": "64"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. In the figure below, \u2220QPR measures 40\u00b0, \u2220PQR measures 105\u00b0, and points Q, R, and S are collinear. What is the measure of \u2220PRS ?", "choices": {"A": "105\u00b0", "B": "125\u00b0", "C": "130\u00b0", "D": "140\u00b0", "E": "145\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. The sum of 2 numbers is 90. The smaller number is 50 less than the larger number. What is the larger number?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": " 40", "C": "45", "D": "70", "E": "80"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. ", "choices": {"A": "-9", "B": "-5", "C": "5", "D": "9", "E": "21"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  What is the value of  when x = 3 and y = -3 ?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-1", "C": "1", "D": "11", "E": "17"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. What is the sum of the 4 binomials listed below?       , \uff0c\uff0c", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Bert's Building Supply receives shipments of only 2 kinds of lawn mowers: Tough Cuts and Easy Pushes. Today's shipment contains 96 lawn mowers with twice as many Tough Cuts as Easy Pushes. How many of these 96 are Tough Cuts?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "32", "C": "47", "D": "48", "E": "64"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Adina plays in a bowling league. Her bowling scores for last week are listed below. What is the median of Adina's bowling scores for last week?\n                         142, 186, 201, 191, 116, 201, 175", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "186", "D": "191", "E": "201"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. The table below shows Shannon's height, in inches, on her birthday from the day she was born (birth) to age 5. What was the average rate of change in Shannon's height, in inches per year, from birth to age 5 ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "7", "E": "14"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. The side lengths, in centimeters, of right triangle \u25b3DEF are given in the figure below. What is the area, in square centimeters, of \u25b3DEF ?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": "96", "C": "120", "D": "160", "E": "192"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Christopher bought 4 cans of soup for a total of $3.36, which included sales tax of $0.16. At the same per-can cost, what is the cost before the sales tax is added for 6 cans of the same soup?", "choices": {"A": "$0.80", "B": "$0.84", "C": "$4.80", "D": "$5.04", "E": "$6.40"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Use the following information to answer questions 14-16.A map of the locations of Marville, Sun Town, and Bright City is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, where coordinates for x and y are given in miles . The coordinates of Marville and Bright City are given, and Sun Town is located along a straight line exactly halfway between Marville and Bright City. Highway H from Marville to Bright City is 390 miles long. Highway K from Sun Town to Bright City is 200 miles long.14. What are the coordinates of Sun Town?", "choices": {"A": "(80, 150)", "B": "(140, 140)", "C": "(150, 80)", "D": "(195, 100)", "E": "(230, 70)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Use the following information to answer questions 14-16.A map of the locations of Marville, Sun Town, and Bright City is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, where coordinates for x and y are given in miles . The coordinates of Marville and Bright City are given, and Sun Town is located along a straight line exactly halfway between Marville and Bright City. Highway H from Marville to Bright City is 390 miles long. Highway K from Sun Town to Bright City is 200 miles long.15. The straight-line distance, in miles, from Marville to Bright City must be:", "choices": {"A": "less than 140.", "B": "between 140 and 300.", "C": "between 300 and 390.", "D": "between 390 and 460.", "E": "more than 460."}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Use the following information to answer questions 14-16.A map of the locations of Marville, Sun Town, and Bright City is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, where coordinates for x and y are given in miles . The coordinates of Marville and Bright City are given, and Sun Town is located along a straight line exactly halfway between Marville and Bright City. Highway H from Marville to Bright City is 390 miles long. Highway K from Sun Town to Bright City is 200 miles long.16. Chelsea's car travels an average of 32 miles per gallon of gas used, and she pays an average of $2.25 per gallon of gas. Chelsea will drive her car along Highway H from Marville to Bright City. To the nearest $1, what will be the total cost of gas that her car uses for the drive?", "choices": {"A": "$ 5.00", "B": "$ 13.00", "C": "$ 14.00", "D": "$27.00", "E": "$32.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Let 0 &lt; a &lt; b &lt; c &lt; d be true for integers a, b, c, and d. Which of the following expressions has the greatest value?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Maurice earns $12.50 per hour for the first 40 hours he works each week. For each hour beyond 40 that he works in 1 week, Maurice earns $18.75 per hour. Last week Maurice earned $931.25. How many hours did Maurice work last week?", "choices": {"A": "23", "B": "30", "C": "55", "D": "63", "E": "76"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. An apartment building is 3 stories tall. Each story has 4 identical apartments. Each apartment's living space consists of 4 rectangular rooms: a bathroom 8 feet by 10 feet, a kitchen 10 feet by 12 feet, a bedroom 12 feet by 12 feet, and a living room 12 feet by 14 feet. What is the area, to the nearest 1,000 square feet, of living space in the 3-story apartment building?", "choices": {"A": "8,000", "B": "6,000", "C": "5,000", "D": "4,000", "E": "3,000"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. The perimeter of a parallelogram is 80 inches, and the length of 1 side is 18 inches. If it can be determined, what are the lengths, in inches, of the other 3 sides?", "choices": {"A": "18, 13, 13", "B": "18, 18, 26", "C": "18, 22, 22", "D": "18, 31, 31", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. The side lengths of right triangle \u25b3LMN are given in centimeters in the figure below. What is tan N ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The empty container shown below is a right rectangular prism with dimensions given in inches. How many cubic inches of liquid are needed to fill the container to 75% of its capacity?", "choices": {"A": "148", "B": "240", "C": "444", "D": "720", "E": "960"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. The length of a rectangle is 4 inches longer than the width. The perimeter of the rectangle is 28 inches. What is the width of the rectangle, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "7", "C": "10", "D": " 12", "E": "14"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The figure below shows 3 different views of the same fair cube. Each face of the cube has 1 design drawn on it. The cube will be rolled once. What is the probability that a face showing a star (\u2605) will be on top?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. For functions f and g defined by and g(x) = 3x - 1, what is the value of f(g(3)) ?", "choices": {"A": "29", "B": "62", "C": "136", "D": "162", "E": "168"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. What is the value of when  and ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "15", "E": "125"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. All of the following statements concern triangles that are similar, congruent, or both. Which statement is FALSE ?", "choices": {"A": "Triangles that are congruent to each other are always similar to each other.", "B": "Lengths of corresponding sides of similar triangles are always equal.", "C": "Lengths of corresponding sides of congruent triangles are always equal.", "D": "Measures of corresponding angles of similar triangles are always equal.", "E": "Measures of corresponding angles of congruent triangles are always equal."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Distinct lines  and m intersect, forming 4 pairs of adjacent angles. Which of the following statements must be true about these 4 pairs of angles?", "choices": {"A": "The difference of the angle measures in each pair is less than 45\u00b0.", "B": "The difference of the angle measures in each pair is 90\u00b0.", "C": "The measure of each angle in each pair is 45\u00b0.", "D": "The sum of the angle measures in each pair is 90\u00b0.", "E": "The sum of the angle measures in each pair is 180\u00b0."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line through (3, 7) and (-2, 4)?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to (2x - 3)(-x - 7) ?", "choices": {"A": "(2x + 3)(x + 7)", "B": "(2x - 3)(x - 7)", "C": "(2x - 3)(x + 7)", "D": "(-2x + 3)(-x - 7)", "E": "(-2x + 3)(x + 7)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Tomas plans to construct a circular fishpond with a diameter of 9 ft. Which of the following is closest to the length, in feet, of the decorative fencing that Tomas needs to enclose the fishpond along its perimeter?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "19", "C": "29", "D": "64", "E": "255"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Ursula will order boxes of red pens and boxes of blue pens for her company. The table below gives the number of pens in each box and the price per box.Ursula will order a total of 50 boxes of pens for a total price of $280. Which of the following systems of equations gives a true relationship between the r boxes of red pens and b boxes of blue pens that Ursula will order ?", "choices": {"A": "     r + b = 505r + 6b = 280", "B": "        r + b = 5015r + 20b = 280", "C": "        r + b = 28015r + 20b = 50", "D": "    5r + 6b = 5015r + 20b = 280", "E": "    5r + 6b = 28015r + 20b = 50"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Which of the following inequalities is an equivalent algebraic expression for the statement below?\n          5 less than the product of 4 and a number n is greater than 28", "choices": {"A": "5 - 4n \uff1e 28", "B": "23 \uff1e 4n", "C": "28 - 4n \uff1e 5", "D": "4n \uff1e 23", "E": "4n - 5 \uff1e 28"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. The quadratic formula gives the 2 roots for the equation . What are the 2 roots of the equation ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. The shaded sector of the circle shown below is bounded by radius AO, radius BO, and minor arc . The length of AO is 4 meters, and the area of the shaded sector is 6\u03c0 square meters. What is the measure of \u2220AOB ?", "choices": {"A": "105\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "135\u00b0", "D": "160\u00b0", "E": "175\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The rental fee for the use of a reception hall is $500. To encourage use of the hall's catering service, the hall's rental fee is reduced by $100 for each group of 20 meals ordered through the hall's catering service. All 20 meals in a group must be ordered for each reduction in the rental fee. One of the following graphs shows the hall's rental fee when 0 to 100 meals are ordered. Which graph is it?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. A line in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane is parallel to the x-axis and 6 coordinate units above it. Which of the following is an equation of this line?", "choices": {"A": "y = 6", "B": "x = 6", "C": "y = 6x", "D": "y = x + 6", "E": "x = y + 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. The figure below shows a 10-foot ladder leaning against a vertical wall. The base of the ladder makes a 65\u00b0 angle with the level ground. Which of the following expressions gives the distance, in feet, between the base of the ladder and the wall?", "choices": {"A": "10 sin 65\u00b0", "B": "10 cos 65\u00b0", "C": "10 tan 65\u00b0", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The only factor that is common to 200 and an integer n is 1. When  is written as a decimal number, what is the minimum number of digits to the right of the decimal point?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Equilateral triangle \u25b3ABC is shown below with each side length given in meters. What is the value of k ?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "1", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. If, then ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "7"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer questions 42- 45.Jin's Office Supply sells different styles of notebooks. The sale price and number of sheets per notebook for 3 styles of notebooks are given in the table below. The sale price is the amount a customer pays for that notebook.42. Which of the following amounts is closest to the average sale price per sheet for a Style B notebook?", "choices": {"A": "$0.01", "B": "$0.02", "C": "$0.03", "D": "$0.12", "E": "$0.83"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer questions 42- 45.Jin's Office Supply sells different styles of notebooks. The sale price and number of sheets per notebook for 3 styles of notebooks are given in the table below. The sale price is the amount a customer pays for that notebook.43. A bin contains 100 Style A notebooks, 100 Style B notebooks, and 100 Style C notebooks. Antoine will select 3 notebooks from the bin. How many different selections of 3 notebook styles are possible?(Note: The order in which the notebooks are selected does not matter.)", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "6", "C": "10", "D": "14", "E": "27"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Use the following information to answer questions 42- 45.Jin's Office Supply sells different styles of notebooks. The sale price and number of sheets per notebook for 3 styles of notebooks are given in the table below. The sale price is the amount a customer pays for that notebook.44. Last week, customers bought 5 times as many Style A notebooks as Style C notebooks, and customers bought 2 times as many Style B notebooks as Style C notebooks. Last week, customers bought 392 notebooks. What total amount did customers pay for the 392 notebooks?", "choices": {"A": "$490.00", "B": "$560.00", "C": "$588.00", "D": "$686.00", "E": "$784.00"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Use the following information to answer questions 42- 45.Jin's Office Supply sells different styles of notebooks. The sale price and number of sheets per notebook for 3 styles of notebooks are given in the table below. The sale price is the amount a customer pays for that notebook.45. The notebook supplier is offering Jin's a Style D notebook that has 60% more sheets than the Style C notebook has. How many sheets does the Style D notebook have?", "choices": {"A": "200", "B": "260", "C": "275", "D": "320", "E": "350"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Given that 3x + 5y = 17 and 2x + 3y = 11, what is the value of x + y ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The least common multiple (LCM) of 2 numbers is 108. The greater of the 2 numbers is 54. What is the maximum value of the other number?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "6", "C": "18", "D": "27", "E": "36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of a line that is perpendicular to 2x- 3y = 9 ?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Which of the following number line graphs is that of the solution set to the inequality -2x + 12 \u2265 20 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. A right prism with triangular bases and with dimensions given in inches is shown below. What is the prism's total surface area, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "120", "B": "204", "C": "228", "D": "240", "E": "264"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. If # represents the operation defined by a # b = a +, then (1 # 2) # 3 =?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "12", "C": "30", "D": "32", "E": "216"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3DEF will be translated 12 coordinate units down and 2 coordinate units right. What will be the coordinates of E after the translation?", "choices": {"A": "(7, -8)", "B": "(6, -7)", "C": "(3, -7)", "D": "(-7, 6)", "E": "(-8, 7)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The product of 2 numbers is 25. If 1 of the numbers is the complex number 4 + 3i, what is the other number?", "choices": {"A": "21 - 3i", "B": "", "C": "4 - 3i", "D": "100 + 75i", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Experimental data is represented in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane by a scatterplot consisting of 6 points: (1, 1.4), (2, 2.9), (3, 3.4), (4, 3.1), (5, 1.9), and (6, 0.2). When all possible real values for a, b, and c are considered, which of the following functions best fits the experimental data?", "choices": {"A": "y = a", "B": "y = ax + b", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. In the figure below, AB is parallel to DE, the measure of \u2220ABC is 49\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220BCD is 137\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220CDE ?", "choices": {"A": "78\u00b0", "B": "88\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "92\u00b0", "E": "96\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. As shown below, 2 circular pulleys with centers 8 inches apart are connected with a tight belt. The belt wraps  of the way around the larger pulley, which has a radius of 5 inches, and  of the way around the smaller pulley, which has a radius of 1 inch. What is the exact length of the belt, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "17\u03c0 + 8", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Given that sin A = and 0\u00b0 \u2264 A &lt; 360\u00b0, what are all possible values of cos A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The lengths of the sides of the triangle shown below are given in meters. Which of the following equations gives the degree measure \u03b8 ?(Note: For any triangle,  , where a, b, and c are the lengths of the sides opposite angles with measures A, B, and C, respectively.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. The sum of the first 30 positive integers is 465. Which of the following is the sum of the first 60 positive integers?", "choices": {"A": "465\u00b2", "B": "930", "C": "1,395", "D": "1,830", "E": "12,865"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. What is the minimum degree possible for the polynomial function whose graph is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "4"}, "correct": "E"}]}